Mustafa Abdul-Kader 1339 N Dearborn St Apt #8B CHICAGO IL 60610 (312) 612-0390 https://muszr.me/ | mustafa@muszr.me

Summary

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the insurance, logistics, financial, and tech industries. Skilled in OOP using modern enterprise-level design patterns with a strong focus in test driven development. Passionate engineering professional with a Bachelor of Applied Science (BASc) focused in Computer Science.

Skills

Languages C# 9, Java 11+, C11, Python, SQL, JavaScript, TypeScript, Dart

Frameworks .NET 4.x, .NET 5, WCF, RESTful Services (Web API 2.0 / JAX-RS), Android SDK, Entity Framework, Dapper, Hibernate, Spring, Micronaut

Continuous Integration and Deployment Git, Jira, TeamCity, TravisCl, Octopus, Jenkins, ECS / ECR / EKS, GCR / GKE

Testing Selenium, Moq, [xnj]Unit, mocha, Protractor, Integration testing

Web Vue.js / Vuex, Angular[Dart/JS], React / Redux, webpack, Highcharts, HTML5 / CSS3, SCSS, LESS

UI WPF, GTK+ Data MSSQL, MongoDb, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Lucene / Elasticsearch, Redis

Environment Win10, Linux, Mac OS, VS Pro 2017, IntelliJ IDEA, VS Code, Photoshop, SSMS, Sequel Pro, Vagrant, Terraform, Tomcat, ELK, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, AWS, GCP, Azure

Experience

MAY 2020 -

FHLBC, Chicago, IL - Software Engineer

- Met with members across the bank to evaluate, shadow, and gather requirements to facilitate efforts in phase one of application build-out
- Contributed to define, implement and lead the efforts of a greenfield web app for the bank leading their modern engineering efforts.
- Responsible for designing and architecting the front-end system and the associated end-to-end testing framework

MAY 2019 - FEB 2020

project44, Chicago, IL - Software Engineer

- Improve the Ocean product offering by increasing test coverage, including new data providers, and updating the codebase to follow best-practices to offer a better product
- Collaborate with PO and PM as well as the data services team to help progress the visibility and tracking of vessels and container
- Convert microservices from a container-based solution to a pod-based solution and updating the deployment pipeline to deploy to EKS instead of ECS (utilizing helm packages)
- Evaluate and gather requirements to facilitate efforts in phase one migration of services from AWS to GCP

APR 2019 -

NVISIA, Chicago, IL - Software Engineer

MAR 2018 - APR 2019

Trustwave Holdings Inc, Chicago, IL - Software Engineer

- Collaborate with Product Management to identify, prioritize and document detailed product requirements
- Design, develop and document application and framework code in Java, Dart, and various query languages
- Work with internal QA team on system, performance and acceptance testing

IUL 2017 - MAR 2018

Falcon Insurance Group, Oak Brook, IL - Application Developer

AUG 2015 - JUL 2017

Falcon Insurance Group, Oak Brook, IL - Application Developer Intern

- Full-stack developer utilizing the .NET stack to build out Windows Services, WPF apps, and modern web-apps
- Responsible for managing and extending web apps that reside on the intranet
- Gain exposure and utilize modern tooling and frameworks to incorporate into projects
- Generate unit tests to maximize code coverage on the applications

Education

DEC 2019

Google Cloud Professional Data Engineer

AUG 2016 - AUG 2017

Saint Xavier University, Chicago, IL - BSCS

Excelled in all coursework.

AUG 2015 - MAY 2016

College of DuPage, Glen Ellyn, IL

Nominated for Phi Theta Kappa, an Honors Society for high academic achievement.